Welcome to our training on the Late Shipment Rate, or LSR.
Today we'll cover what the LSR is and how it affects sellers in the Amazon Store.
Let's start by defining LSR.
LSR measures the percentage of orders where shipment confirmation occurs after the expected ship
date.
You can find the expected ship date in order details.
It's important to note that LSR only applies to seller-fulfilled orders, also known as merchant-
fulfilled, or MFN.
To calculate your LSR, your total orders are divided by those that were ship-confirmed late.
So if you've had 100 orders in the last 10 days and two of them were shipped after the expected
ship date, you'll have an LSR of 2%.
Sellers must maintain an LSR under 4% to continue selling in the Amazon Store.
An LSR over 4% can result in account deactivation.
To view your LSR, head to the Performance tab in Seller Central and select Account Health.
In the Shipping Performance section, select Late Shipment Rate.
On this page, you'll see your LSR calculated for the last 10 and 30 days.
It's important to confirm orders by their expected ship dates so your customers can see their order
status online.
Confirming late can lead to negative customer experiences, increased claims, negative feedback and
customer contacts.
If your LSR is in jeopardy, you may be notified and given 30 days to remedy the situation.
If you do not take action, you could risk account deactivation.
Now let's review some top tips for improving and maintaining your LSR.
First, be sure you only list items you're able to ship by or before their expected ship date.
Next, work with your carriers to ensure they will be able to pick up your packages and scan them
on time.
Finally, ensure you confirm shipments with valid tracking information as soon as you hand over packages
to the carrier.
It's also possible that your business has grown during your time in the Amazon store to the point
where you need to hire more staff to stay on top of orders.
Create a daily reminder to check for and prepare orders.
Making this a part of your daily routine can help you always ship on time.
You can also use Amazon's Buy Shipping Services to simplify the shipping process and remove your
need to confirm shipping.
To learn more about Amazon Buy Shipping Services, search for Buy Shipping in Seller University.
Preparing for increased order volume during key sales periods like the run-up to holiday seasons
can help you maintain a healthy LSR.
Finally, always check your account health dashboard regularly for notifications.
This concludes our training on the late shipment rate.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.